<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arcade Machine on Web Portfolio of John Westhoff</title>
    <link>https://www.johnbot.me/series/arcade-machine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Arcade Machine on Web Portfolio of John Westhoff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 01:52:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.johnbot.me/series/arcade-machine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>An Arcade Machine (Mostly) From Scratch</title>
      <link>https://www.johnbot.me/post/arcademachine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 01:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.johnbot.me/post/arcademachine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project is one that has been in development for a few years now, and it probably
won&amp;rsquo;t be finished for a few more. It is one that has grown in scope considerably, and
is really the result of several smaller projects. Currently, the end goal is to have
a fully working arcade machine of my very own - running a game I wrote on hardware I built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project began at the end of grade school when I decided to try making my own fighting game.
I got far enough, and ended with a simple game with three characters. I revisited the game
at the end of high school when I decided to make it about my highschool robotics team,
&lt;a href=&#34;www.robovikings.com&#34;&gt;The Fighting RoboVikings&lt;/a&gt;. I got a few of the team members to design
characters, and I started adding them to the game. (It quickly became an arms race to make
the most unfair character, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t bother me.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is here that I decided that it would be really cool to turn the game into an arcade machine,
so I got to work planning out the machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by making the control panel. I ordered some
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ebay.com/itm/HAPP-Arcade-Control-Panel-Kit-your-choice-of-HAPP-14-Push-Buttons-2-Joystick-/251343306708?hash=item3a853a7fd4&#34;&gt;arcade supplies&lt;/a&gt;, as well as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.ti.com/Tiva-C-LaunchPad.aspx&#34;&gt;TI Stellaris Launchpad&lt;/a&gt;
(Links to the successor, the Tiva-C launchpad, as the Stellaris is now defunct.) I modified the example
USB keyboard code, and I used Microsoft Word (of all programs&amp;hellip;) to make the button layout.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;buttonlayout.png&#34; alt=&#34;Why&amp;#39;d I use Microsoft Word for this? Why only five buttons? These are my only regrets.&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Why&amp;#39;d I use Microsoft Word for this? Why only five buttons? These are my only regrets.
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;With the buttons and joysticks laid out, I got to work cutting and drilling a piece of, um, well,
I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly what kind of plastic it is, but the office had lots of sheets lying around that
they said I could use, and, well, anything free is automatically the best value. Once I was done,
I installed the arcade components.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;panel1.png&#34; alt=&#34;I bought all the spade connectors my local Radio Shack had for this...&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        I bought all the spade connectors my local Radio Shack had for this...
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;panel2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Wiring came next. I know I disappointed at least three people with this rat&amp;#39;s nest, but I was excited.&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Wiring came next. I know I disappointed at least three people with this rat&amp;#39;s nest, but I was excited.
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;tryingitout.png&#34; alt=&#34;I was eager to test it. The first game played? X-Men, because who can say no to the Master of Magnet.&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        I was eager to test it. The first game played? X-Men, because who can say no to the Master of Magnet.
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Once everything worked, I took an old Compaq CRT monitor and my control panel and took some measurements. Using those,
I drew up some parts in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ptc.com/cad/creo/parametric&#34;&gt;CREO Parametric&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;crtsize.png&#34; alt=&#34;I just wish the CRT was a bit bigger...&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        I just wish the CRT was a bit bigger...
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;crtdepth.png&#34; alt=&#34;Err, maybe not.&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Err, maybe not.
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;panelsize.png&#34; alt=&#34;I don&amp;#39;t know why I had to measure this either.&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        I don&amp;#39;t know why I had to measure this either.
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I printed out drawings for each part and bought some 2x4s from Home Depot. My neighbor had a yard sale and sold me
a chop saw for $10 (what perfect timing!), and I cut out all the pieces, and a few friends and I spent a warm summer
night screwing them together. I took an old, broken, Windows XP Dell laptop, locked it down, uninstalled almost everything, and set it up to auto login and auto start my game. Oh, and when I say I uninstalled almost everything,
I meant the hardware, too. It has no screen half and no DVD reader, as those aren&amp;rsquo;t things arcade machines need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;lappy.png&#34; alt=&#34;I think it fell down the stairs once, so the screen was already mostly broken off.&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        I think it fell down the stairs once, so the screen was already mostly broken off.
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, I added supports for the CRT and set everything up. I ordered some speakers from Amazon, and it has
been running in my room ever since. My friends and I played a few rounds and remembered our high school days, and
then laughed at some absurd glitches that I now have to leave in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;lastweek.png&#34; alt=&#34;The machine as of last week.&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        The machine as of last week.
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The source for the unfinished game is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/s/yrcn0o2q5vyxc9o/fighting.gm81?dl=0&#34;&gt;in my Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The source for the Stellaris Launchpad which handles the arcade buttons and joysticks
is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://1drv.ms/f/s!AvygQw6LWI-Xg9IkRCoJd-C3BA9e1A&#34;&gt;in my OneDrive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CREO Parametric files for the machine frame are also available &lt;a href=&#34;https://1drv.ms/f/s!AvygQw6LWI-XgvdcD70bq_TbV7BHyQ&#34;&gt;in my OneDrive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>